现在你会记得我们的请求字符串有
now as you'll recall our request string has
多行，我们需要解析第一行
multiple lines and we need to parse that first line
所以我们知道如何回应
so we know how to respond
那就对了
that's right
我们需要解析请求字符串来创建地图
we need to parse the request string to create a map
看起来像这样
that looks like this
现在一个长生不老药地图从这个%开始
now an elixir map starts with this %
然后我们在这里有一个花括号
and then we have a curly brace here
最后是一个花括号
and a curly brace at the end
然后在这里我们有键值对
and then inside of here we have key value pairs
在这种情况下，关键在哪里
where the keys in this case are
长生不老药原子就像红宝石符号
elixir atoms which are like ruby symbols
又是一个常量，名字就是它的值
again it's a constant whose name is its value
所以我们有了关键方法
so we've got the key method
并且值获取路径是狂野的东西
and the values get path is wild things
显然我们想要
and obviously we want to
在这里和这里替换这些硬编码值
replace these hard coded values here and here
与此请求字符串中的任何内容
with whatever is in this request string
所以让我们点燃性爱，让我们玩吧
so let's fire up sex and let's play
围绕如何解析请求字符串
around with how to parse the request string
好吧 性爱
alright sex
然后我将粘贴我们的请求字符串
and then I'm going to paste in our request string
这是一个这里的码头
which is a here dock
这样我们就有了
just so we have that available
所以要解析这个字符串，我们将使用
so to parse this string we're going to use a
字符串函数
string function
你可以使用方便的 h
and you can use the handy h
ix 内部的函数以获得一些帮助
function inside of ix to get some help
我们可以说字符串点是模块的名称
we can say string dot that's the name of the module
那么如果你只是点击标签
then if you just hit tab
它使用自动完成向我们展示所有功能
it uses auto completion to show us all the functions
我们可以打电话
we can call
并注意有三个拆分功能
and notice that there are three split functions
分裂一分裂二分裂分裂三
split one split split two and split split three
这里的数字表示有多少
the number here indicates how many
函数期望的参数
arguments the function expects
它通常被称为函数
it's often referred to as the functions airily
所以一个模块可以定义
so a module can define
多个同名函数
multiple functions with the same name
和不同的能力
and a different ability
然后函数是唯一的
and then the function is uniquely
由其包含模块标识
identified by its containing module
在这种情况下，字符串模块
in this case the string module
它的名字和迭代
its name and iterate
在这种情况下，我们将使用拆分两个
in this case we're going to use split two
那么如果我完成
so then if I just complete
这与拆分和命中返回很好
this with split and hit return well
它给了我们一点帮助
it gives us a little bit of help
关于如何调用 split 有一些例子
about how to call split with some examples there
所以 split 返回一个列表
so split returns a list
我将在一个名为 lines 的变量中捕获它
which I'm going to capture in a variable called lines
我们将调用字符串拆分
we're going to call string split
我有要求
I have the request
这是它的第一个论点
that's the first argument to it
然后我们将其拆分
and then we're going to split it
在新线上
on a new line
因为
because
记住我们想要的多行请求
remember a request of multiple lines that we want each
行成为该列表中的一个元素
line to be an element in that list
那只会以这种方式将其拆分为新行
that will just split it on new lines that way
这给了我们所有行的列表
and that gives us back a list of all the lines
那么如果我们想要第一行，我们可以使用
then if we wanted the first line we could use
list 模块有一个名为 first 的函数
the list module has a function called first
并将其传递到列表中
and pass it in a list
那只会给我们第一行
and that will just give us the first line
这是我们感兴趣的请求行
it's the request line that we're interested in
所以另一种方法是使用管道
so another way to do this will be using a pipe
所以我们留在第一行等于请求
so we stay first line equals request
管它进入字符串拆分
pipe that into string split
现在第一个参数是请求
now the first argument to that is the request
第二个论点是要拆分的内容
the second argument is what to split on
好吧，第一个论点将被输入
well the first argument is going to be piped in
从左边
from the left
所以我们只需要指定
so we just have to specify the
第二个论点
second argument
这将返回一个列表
that's going to return a list
所以我们可以进一步管道
and so we can pipe that further
进入
into
首先列出
list first
我们得到同样的东西
we get the same thing
所以让我们继续复制这一行
so let's just go ahead and copy this line at well
将其粘贴到我们的解析函数中
paste it into our parse function
我会粘贴它来代替我们在那里做的事情
and I'll just paste it to replace our to do there
所以现在我们有了第一个
so now that we have the first
线我们现在需要拆分它
line we now need to split it
分成自己的部分
into its own parts
我只是要清理这个
I'm just going to clean this up
我们有第一行
and we have our first line
记住已经存储了
remember that's already been stored
现在我们只想拆分第一行
and now we just want to split this first line
分为这三个不同的部分
into these three different parts
所以我们要说部分等于字符串拆分
so we're going to say parts equals string split
我们将采取第一行
we'll take the first line
在这种情况下，我们将根据空格对其进行拆分
in this case we'll split it based on a space
我们得到一个包含三个元素的列表
and we get back a list of three elements with
这些部分中的每一个
each of those parts
但我们只对路径中的方法感兴趣
but we're only interested in the method in the path
不是真正的协议
not really the protocol
所以解决这些问题的一种方法是使用 e new
so one way to get at these would be to use the e new
内置在 elixir 中的模块
module that's built into elixir
并且有一个应用程序功能
and there's an app function
在这种情况下，您给它一个列表，然后
you give it a list in this case parts and then
你想要的东西的索引
the index of the thing you want
所以索引零会给我们get方法
so index zero would give us the method which is get
和索引一
and index one
会给我们路径
would give us the path
现在可以了，但它不是惯用的
now that works but it's not idiomatic
Elixir 代码模式匹配为我们提供了更多
elixir code pattern matching gives us a more
优雅而强大的方式来做同样的事情
elegant and powerful way to do the same thing
模式匹配对你如何
and pattern matching is a huge influence on how you
设计灵药代码
design elixir code
这也是一个重要的
it's also an important
如果您从 oo 过渡，则不同
difference if you're transitioning from oo
到函数式编程
to functional programming
所以让我们看看
so let's look at
一些性模式匹配的例子
some examples of pattern matching in sex
所以这里有一些熟悉的东西让我们说一个等于一个
so here's something familiar let's say a equals one
this 的作用是绑定值
what this does is that binds the value
在右手侧
on the right hand side
在这种情况下一个
one in this case
到左侧的变量 a
to the variable a that's on the left hand side
我们会认识到这只是分配
and we would recognize that as just assignment
所以现在 a 的值为 1
so now the value of a is one
但有趣的是等号运算符
but the interesting thing is the equal operator
灵丹妙药不是任务
an elixir isn't assignment
就像我们习惯用其他语言一样
like we're used to in other languages
它实际上被称为 mash 运算符
it's actually called the mash operator
所以检查一下
so check this out
一等于返回值一的井
one equals a well that returns the value one
所以这里发生的是
so what's happening here is
长生不老药总是试图使左手边
elixir always tries to make the left hand side
这和右手边一样
this same as the right hand side
如果垫子成功
if the mat succeeds
它返回匹配表达式的结果
it returns the result of the match expression
这正是这里发生的事情，我们找回了一个
and that's exactly what happened here we got back one
这场比赛是因为左右手边
this match is because both the left and right hand side
等于一
are equal to one
但是如果左边和右边会发生什么
but what happens if the left and the right
不匹配所以两个等于一个
don't match so two equals a
好吧，我们找回了比赛的气氛
well we get back a match air
因为 a 的值为 1
because the value of a is one
和两个相等的一个是匹配的空气
and two equal one is a match air
现在如果左边有一个变量
now if there's a variable on the left
和右边的值
and a value on the right
然后变量被绑定
then the variable gets bound
使匹配成功的值
to the value to make the match succeed
所以如果我们说 a 等于二
so if we say a equals two
好吧，我们在左边有一个变量
well we've got a variable on the left
和右边的值
and a value on the right
所以它会将两个绑定到变量 a
so it's going to bind two to the variable a
这是一场比赛，所以我们得到了两个
and it's a match so we get back two
作为该表达式的结果
as the result of that expression
这有效地将 a 重新绑定到两个的值
this effectively rebinds a to the value of two
它从一开始
it started off with the value of one
但我们将其反弹到 2
but we rebound it to a value of two
所以现在如果我们说二等于一
so now if we say two equals a
那些会匹配，我们会再次获得两个
will those match and we get back two again
现在有时你不想重新绑定变量
now sometimes you don't want to rebind the variable
相反，你想要一个
instead you want a
模式匹配变量现有值
pattern match against the variables existing value
在这种情况下，您需要使用 pin 运算符
in that case you need to use the pin operator
看起来像这样
it looks like that
如果我们说 a 等于三
if we say a equals three
好吧，这是一个匹配错误
well it's a match error
注意它没有尝试绑定值 3
notice it didn't try to bind the value three
对变量 a
to the variable a
相反，它查看了 a 的现有值
instead it looked at the existing value of a
在这种情况下是二，不等于三
which is two in this case and that doesn't equal three
那么这在实践中如何有用
so how is this useful in practice
好吧，实际上模式匹配被全部使用
well actually pattern matching is used all
在长生不老药程序中的位置
over the place in elixir programs
我们会在整个课程中看到很多例子
and we'll see many examples throughout this course
和最
and one of the most
使用模式匹配的强大方法是破坏
powerful ways to use pattern matching is to destruct
复杂数据类型
complex data types
比如列表
such as lists
所以让我们从头开始
so let's just start at the top again
假设我有一个清单一二和三
let's say I've got a list one two and three
我们可以说等于一
we can say equal one
二三如此
two and three so
左右是一样的
the right and the left are the same
我们有一场比赛
and we have a match
但我们想重组这个列表
but we'd like to restructure this list
这是在右手边
that's on the right hand side
为了做到这一点，我们可以把
and to do that we can put
左侧的变量
variables on the left hand side
所以在这个位置我只会说第一个
so here in this position I'll just say 1st
如果我们在那里击中返回，那就是一场比赛 1 2 3
if we hit return there well it's a match 1 2 3
所以变量首先在左侧
so that variable first on the left hand side
绑定到值一
got bound to the value one
因为那是位置
because that's in the position
右侧列表的
of the list on the right hand side
让整场比赛成功
to make this whole match succeed
所以现在如果我们先看看变量
so now if we look at the variable first
好吧，它的价值是一
well it has the value one
现在重要的是要注意，长生不老药只会改变
now it's important to note that elixir will only change
左侧变量的值
the value of a variable that's on the left hand side
所以如果我们在这里有一个变量
so if we had a variable over here
它不会尝试将其绑定到任何东西
it wouldn't try to bind it to anything
所以现在如果我们想重组我们的清单
so now if we wanted to restructure our list
再远一点
a little bit further
我们可以使用多个变量
we can use multiple variables on the
右侧
right hand side
所以这可能是第一个
so this might be first
我们会把这两个留在中间
we'll leave the two in there in the middle
如果我们在这里使用 last
and if we use last here
我们得到的第一个是一个，最后一个是三个
what we've got first being one and last being three
所以你可以想到左边
so you can think of the left side
作为您尝试成功的模式
as a pattern you're trying to successfully
与右侧的术语匹配
match with the term on the right hand side
在这种情况下，右边和左边
in this case the right and the left
具有相同的结构
have the same structure
有三个元素列表
there are three element lists
右边的字面两个
the literal two on the right hand side
匹配字面量二
matches the literal two
在左侧的相同位置
in the same position on the left hand side
然后为了使匹配值一被绑定
and then to make the match the value one is bound
到变量 first 并且值 3 被绑定
to the variable first and the value three is bound
到变量最后
to the variable last
所以特定值之一不匹配
so one of a specific value doesn't match
比如让我们把二改成七
like let's change two to seven
那么在那种情况下
well in that case
两个文字在中间不匹配
the two literals don't match in the middle
所以我们在这里得到一场比赛
so we get a match here
现在这并不奇怪
now that's not surprising
但它表明我们可以使用模式匹配
but it demonstrates that we can use pattern matching
既要检查
to both check
字面值
literal values
并提取值
and extract values
现在如果结构尺寸不同怎么办
now what if the structures are different sizes
就像让我们一起删除这七个
like let's remove this seven all together
是的，我们这里只有一个包含两个元素的列表
yeah we'll just have a two element list over here
那也是一个匹配错误
well that's a match error as well
所以现在我们知道如何申请了
so now we know how to apply
模式匹配来解析我们的字符串
pattern matching to parse our string
是的，我们在那里有第一行
yeah we've got our first line in there
请记住，这是在第一行变量中
remember that's in the first line variable
所以我们可以拆分字符串拆分
so we can split it string split
第一行拆分它
1st line split it
在空格上，我们知道这将返回一个列表
on spaces and we know that's going to return a list
像那样，让我们匹配
like that so let's make it match
这将是我们想要捕捉的方法
this is going to be the method we want to capture that
在方法变量中
in a method variable
这将是道路
this is going to be the path
这将是版本
and that's going to be the version
这是一个匹配方法是 get
and that's a match method is get
路径是野物
path is wild things
并且版本是http一腐一
and the version is http one rot one
现在我们对http版本并不感兴趣
now we're not really interested in the http version
所以你可以做的另一件事是
so another thing you can do is
在这里使用下划线
just use an underscore right here
这将匹配
which will match
右手边的任何东西
anything on the right hand side
它基本上是一张外卡
it's basically a wild card
所以现在我们可以继续把它从这里复制出来
so now we can go ahead and copy this out of here
将其粘贴回我们的解析函数
paste it back in our parse function
所以这条线
so this line
分配第一行，所以我们可以在这里粘贴
assigns the first line so we can just paste in here
分割第一行的东西
the thing that splits that first line
并给我们方法路径
and gives us the method path
我们忽略了http协议
and we ignore the http protocol
现在我们可以改变我们的地图来使用
and now we can change our map to use
解析的值而不是这些硬编码的值
the parsed values rather than these hardcoded value
所以这将是方法
so this is going to be method
并且路径的值将是
and the value of path is going to be
路径变量中有什么
what's ever in the path variable
我们可以删除这个 con 变量，因为
and we can remove this co n variable because
这是函数的最后一个表达式
this is the last expression of the function
所以这就是隐式返回的内容
so this is what's going to be implicitly returned
所以零件将返回一张地图
so parts is going to return a map which is
正是我们想要的
exactly what we want
所以这会起作用
so this will work
但我们可以使用管道使其更简洁
but we can make it more concise using pipes
所以让我们重新安排一下
so let's rearrange this a bit
我们将在第一行删除这个临时变量
we'll get rid of this temporary variable first line
所以我们接受我们的请求，这是一个多行字符串
so we take our request which is a multi line string
我们想将其拆分为行列表
we want to split it into a list of lines
然后我们想得到第一行
then we want to get the first line
然后我们要先拆分
then we want to split that first
分为三个部分
line into its three parts
所以我要把它拿出来
so I'm just going to take this out
将其剪切到我的复制粘贴缓冲区中
cut it out here into my copy paste buffer
我们真正想做的是管道
what we really want to do is pipe
这个表达式的结果
the result of this expression
这将是一个字符串
which is going to be a string
进入这个功能
into this function
并且管道会做到它会供应
and the pipe will do that it will supply
第一行是那里的第一个参数
first line is the first argument there
所以管道将提供该参数
so the pipe will supply that argument
然后这一切都会回来
and then all this is going to return
这又是
this again
所以你可以把它想象成一个层次结构
so you can kind of think of this as a hierarchy
管道
of pipelines
我们在这里有我们的高级管道请求
we've got our high level pipeline here request
一路转化为响应
transforming all the way into response
然后在管道的这个特定步骤中
and then in this particular step of the pipeline
我们在这里进入这个管道
we get into this pipeline here
这确实与那个相关
which does sort of sub related to that
你几乎可以把这些管道想象成
you can almost think of these pipelines as being
分形我们可以拥有其中之一
fractal we could have one of these
调用一个函数，然后执行另一个管道
call a function that then does a whole another pipeline
所以它有点像管道一直向下
so it's kind of like pipelines all the way down
我们会看到很多
we're going to see a lot
更多模式匹配示例
more examples of pattern matching going forward
虽然现在
for now though
这个转变完成了
this transformation is complete
接下来我们准备更新响应正文
and we're ready to update the response body next